<doc><title>The fuel of brain </title><author>Anupam Kumar</author><publishdate>Published On July 20th, 2014</publishdate><body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=http://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/dopamine&gt;Dopamine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; plays one of the most vital roles in the almost every behavioral process we perform. Everything good or bad about our behavior is linked to this aqueous chemical in our brain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The part of the brain, that connects the higher, complex brain to the simple, primitive brain, is the &lt;i&gt;Limbic system&lt;/i&gt;. This is the center of emotions, memories and arousal (sexual and non-sexual (like drug etc)). This is part of the system where all behaviors patterns, habits and addictions are formed. These patterns are formed in the form of &lt;i&gt;neural reward circuits.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=http://gettingstronger.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Limbic-System.png&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 



&lt;p&gt;What is a reward circuit ? The primitive brain is basically responsible for keeping us motivated. Motivated to do what ? Motivated to :

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Survive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thrive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reproduce&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Play&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learn&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Socialize&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;..etc&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; Every activity we do requires us to be motivated to do it. When we feel motivated and we actually achieve our goals, we were motivated to set in the first place, we feel happy and pleasure.  What is happening here ? &lt;i&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;To feel motivated part of the limbic system secretes &lt;a href=http://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/dopamine target=_blank&gt;dopamine&lt;/a&gt;. When a goal is reached another part of the limbic system receives &lt;a href=http://www.chm.bris.ac.uk/motm/serotonin/home1.htm target=_blank&gt;serotonin&lt;/a&gt; through the blood brain barrier&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/i&gt; When dopamine is transmitted through the neural networks of the brain, it tells every part of the brain to &lt;b&gt;\&quot;Go Do it!\&quot;&lt;/b&gt;. And when serotonin are transmitted through the neural networks of the brain, it tells every part of the brain &lt;b&gt;\&quot;Great work! Well done!\&quot;&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is what a reward circuit is. The whole presence of dopamine and eventual presence of seratonin. Notice how each feeling is so emotional. It\'s all about feelings with the brain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the subsequent articles I will talk about importance of this reward circuit in formation of memories, behavior patterns, habits and addictions. &lt;u&gt;Stay tuned...&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</body><references></references></doc>