<list>
    <title>Best PC Video Games Francises Ever!</title>
    <author>Anupam Kumar</author>
    <publishdate>2nd March, 2014</publishdate>
    <thumbnail_type>Images</thumbnail_type>
    <thumbnail_w>100%</thumbnail_w>

    <items>
        <item>
            <rank>10</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://wallpapersus.com/wallpapers/2013/08/Deus-Ex-Human-Revolution-768x1366.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Deus Ex series</itemname>
            <description>Deus Ex was a very serious game project from Edios. This game was primarily geared towards mature audience, therefore it was not a big commencial success, because it did not appeal to a wide audience. Not only was it a great commentary on society at large. But it introduced revolutionary game mechanics. The game was a absolute challenge and had a very hard learning curve. Citics everywhere have hailed this game and it's successor Deus Ex: Machina as revolutionary.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>9</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://www.gamerepublic.it/wp-content/uploads/Monkey-Island-SE-Wallpaper.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Monkey Island series</itemname>
            <description>Follow the adventures of the lovable character Guybrush Threepwood in this full-filled adveture. I call this game and many other games by Lucas Arts as the conceptual forefather to narrative games like Walking Dead.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>8</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://wallike.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Splinter-Cell-Blacklist-2013-640x360.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Splinter Cell series</itemname>
            <description>If there is any game that changed the way we percive third-person combact games, it has to be Splinter Cell. Not only was a 3rd person game. It was a stealth game that made us all reimagine player-object interaction. You could run on walks, climb virtually anything and go virtually anywhere Sam Fisher wanted to. With a very engaging storyline and awesome steath mechanics, splinter cell can be seen as a forefather to the other successful francishes like Assasin's creed</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>7</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://hdwallsize.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Crysis-Wallpaper-HD-Dekstop.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Crysis series</itemname>
            <description>You may have the world fastest supercomputer finding the cure for Cancer, but it's all moot if it can't run Crysis on maximum settings! Crytek's Crysis has cemented their place to be extremely revolutionary francishes because of their incredibly high-end graphics. Every gamer looks forward to the next Crysis because it's a benchmark in terms of game graphics.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>6</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://fc09.deviantart.net/fs70/i/2013/179/d/f/bioshock_infinite_wallpaper_by_tow_mah-d6b0r2r.png</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Bioshock series</itemname>
            <description>Bioshock is well known among gamer community as a game franchise that may not be very technically superior, but having amazingly fanstastical and engaging storylines. Primarily geared, towards mature audience, System shock / Bioshock have always managed to shock us with their content and controveries. It's a shame that the studio has decided to close.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>5</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://images3.alphacoders.com/155/155819.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>The Elder Scrolls series</itemname>
            <description>A few game franchises have as much critical acclaim and success as the Elder Scrolls game has. The first Elder Scrolls came out for the DOS in 1994, and we were all amazed back then by it's non-linear and open gameplay. The last installment of Elder Scrolls : Skyrim was a phenomenal sucess and an absolute immersive and engaging experience. Bethesda has been doing justice to this title and we gamers are grateful to it's creativity!</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>4</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://fc02.deviantart.net/fs71/i/2011/056/1/f/starcraft2_wallpaper_zerg_by_avulture-d3ad2lj.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Starcraft series</itemname>
            <description>Ask any strategy gamer of what their most enjoyable RTS experience was ? The answer 9/10 times will be Starcraft. In 1998 Blizzard released Starcraft with quickly became a cult classic. This game was so widely well-recieved that gamers in Korea/Japan/US would host tournaments with price money of hundreds of thousands of dollars! Starcraft was one RTS game that hit the balance between managing your economy and military which was not stressful.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>3</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://www.wallpapersdesign.net/wallpapers/2013/05/Unreal-Tournament-3-600x960.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Unreal &amp; Unreal Tournament series</itemname>
            <description>Unreal today is synonymous with the most popular 3D game engine used by all other game dev studios. But, back in the day Unreal was synonymous with incredibly fast-paced mayhem and death and destruction in an arena with upto 32 other players across the internet. Unreal tournament along with it's arch-rival Quake III : Arena redefined multiplayer combat before CounterStike was even around. A few other labels have had so much impact on FPS genre as Unreal has had.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>2</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://www.paaat.com/v2/downloads/wallpapers/hl2-02w.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Half-Life series</itemname>
            <description>Speaking of influence, impact and game-changing features (literally), who can argue the importance of Half-Life, Half-Life 2, Gary's Mod, Counter Strike, Team Fortress, Portal and so many other mods, spins thereof on the games industry. The Valve's steam engine powered all these games and all these games had unparallelled realism built into it, in terms of physics and lighting etc. And also, let's not ignore the fact that Half-life and Half-life 2 had absolutely georgeous storylines and very dark and engaging atmosphere! If I need to explain to you why Half-life 2 is here in the list then you probably cannot call yourself a gamer.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
        <item>
            <rank>1</rank>
            <thumbnail>http://windows8wallpaper.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/gta-5-wallpaper-hd-1366x768.jpg</thumbnail>
            <itemname>Grand Theft Auto series</itemname>
            <description>Enter some small time crook looking for a way to make doe in a mean city. And that's where the game leaves you. It's now upto you to do whatever you want to get what you want. GTA is an epitome of open-world game, with the later games like GTA4 and GTA5, having potentially infinite gameplayablity. GTA not only is a technical masterpiece, but its a the ultimate parody of contemporary pop culture today. GTA is something that everyone should play once in his/her life, regardless of them being gamers or not.</description>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
        </item>
    </items>
</list>
