<list><title>My Favourite videogames characters...So Far</title><author>Anupam</author><publishdate>Published On 14th July, 2014</publishdate><thumbnail_type>Images</thumbnail_type><thumbnail_w>100%</thumbnail_w><items><item><rank>10</rank><thumbnail>http://img2.wikia.nocookie.net/__cb20121121055855/borderlands/images/8/8d/Tiny_Tina_DLC_Intro.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Tiny Tina</itemname><description>13 year demolitions expert high on Caffeine, Tiny Tina started out as one of the minor characters in Borderlands series. But she was so well received and became so popular among the fans that she became a playable character in one of the Borderlands 2 DLCs. 



What is memorable about her strange dialogues and teenager wisdom... It\'s hard to describe really. Check this out. &lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ICPR6E4AtfQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>9</rank><thumbnail>http://a2.ec-images.myspacecdn.com/images01/102/5995d21fafff5c7d412776efb8f6a1ea/l.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Guybrush Treepwood</itemname><description>Guybrush is the a very strange name, but it is name of the lovable protagonist of the Monkey Island adventure game series. Guybrush\'s adventures are always in funny, amusing, with a tinge of sarcasm. All he ever wanted was to be become a pirate and marry his love Elaine. And in trying to do so each and everytime he invariably pits himself against the dreaded undead-ghost-zombie pirate LeChuck. Fortunately for Guybrush, Lady luck and some amount of intelligence is always at his side and he always manages to overcome the odds in hilarious ways. 



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HGlxdKGiEqU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>8</rank><thumbnail>http://megahdwall.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Half-Life-Nature-You-Are-Viewing-Video-Games-Splinter-Cell-Sam-Fisher-Action-Scenes-373322.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Sam Fisher</itemname><description>The protagonist of Splinter Cell series has a dark and mysterious past that is gradually revealed as you play through the series. One of the best stealth games, splinter cell tells the story of this character that will endear him.&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7wnZrIDBuAc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>7</rank><thumbnail>http://static.tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pub/images/cate_archer_nolf2.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Cate Archer</itemname><description>For those of us who grew up in the 90s, we remember Cate Archer as the classiest and most elegant spy to ever save the free world from HARM and other evil. Cate Archer from No one lives forever is a smart, quick-witted spy who always gets the job done. He style of undertaking missions and journey from a spy in training (in NOLF) to 

a legitmate super-spy (in NOLF-2) is a fantastically well written story and a well executed plot, constructed in great detail. And that is why she deserves a spot on this list.&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/spxATsZoYIg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>6 </rank><thumbnail>http://img2.wikia.nocookie.net/__cb20130403085051/theinventory/images/b/b0/Glados.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>GlaDOS </itemname><description>GlaDOS is the only companion you (as Chell) have throughout the portal series. Though she is arrogant and talks down to you all the time (even trying to kill you), would you talk down to everyone else if you were an all powerful being too ? 





In portal 2 players come to know about GlaDOS's past and realize that she is not only the most powerful being, but also the most selfless.&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/q5kkwermfs4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;br/&gt;
She is really the smartest being on Earth too... Look her sing her own composition!&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jLpe2lQPyBk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>5</rank><thumbnail>http://img2.hebus.com/hebus_2004/08/20/preview/040820122759_52.jpg</thumbnail><itemname> Arthas Menethil</itemname><description>The protagonist and the antagonist of Warcraft 3 : Reign of Chaos and Warcraft 3 : The frozen throne. Arthas\'s story is probably the greatest story ever written for an Strategy game. Through the story we see the transformation of a kindhearted, gentle prince, whose only desire is to stop "the scourge" that afflicts his father\'s kingdom to a ruthless king who has lost his soul to save his kingdom... If you have not play warcraft 3 then you don\'t know what are great story you have missed through it\'s campaign. &lt;br/&gt;

 

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/IIz4lgxlLHw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>4</rank><thumbnail>http://static.comicvine.com/uploads/original/11113/111136881/3541485-tp.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Trevor Phillips</itemname><description>The owner of Trevor Philips Enterprises/Industries, is one of Three wonderfully written GTA 5 characters in their story mode. Trevor is an amoral maniac who, in his own eyes is "keeping it real" and doing what he thinks is right. An anarchist, who does not want to hurt people who respect (and agree to do his bidding). Chemistry between Trevor and Micheal (the other main character) is brilliantly crafted and your decisions in the game shape their relation. Check out some of Trevor's antics here. 
&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/f8O2cAyColY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>3</rank><thumbnail>http://static.comicvine.com/uploads/original/14/146226/2859857-hitman_agent_47.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Agent 47</itemname><description>The Agency\'s most lethal weapon, Agent 47, the greatest contract hitman is one of the most mysterious and well flushed out characters. Through the games in the series, like Splinter cell, his history is revealed slowly. Players cannot help feel empathy and communion for the angel of who deal in only money and death, who\'s only identity is a number, especially after he he was double-crossed by the only person who he could trust.&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/GrDajo6zSho" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>2</rank><thumbnail>http://img3.wikia.nocookie.net/__cb20131231014849/assassinscreedbr/pt/images/c/c6/Ezio-Auditore-De-Firenze-by-sXeven.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Ezio</itemname><description>Ezio Auditore da Firenze is the protagonist of the Assassin\'s Creed series who starts out as care-free freethinker and transforms into the leader of the Assasin\'s order. He was the first existential philosopher ever, way before, Satre or Dostovosky and his story is one of the most moving and beautifully written I have ever come across. &lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/p4D8su84xRM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>1</rank><thumbnail>http://i1-news.softpedia-static.com/images/extra/GAMES2/large/twds2e1/twds2e1txtscr_001-large.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Clementine</itemname><description>Clementine a normal 8 year old girl in Atlanta suberb, who is caught in the middle of zombie outbreak. She is found and saved by Lee Everett, who is protagonist of the first installment. While playing the game, players quickly find out that she is the main character in the Walking Dead series (from tell-tale games, not another generic, cash-grap FPS from Activision). 



In the first season she is a non-playable character who is always with and protected by Lee. The player develops a great fondness and a very emotional connection with Clementine, with an urge to protect and keep her from harm\'s way. After an  extremely emotional ending to the first season, Clementine become the main playable character in the second season. 



Can a person love a video game character (like one would a little child) ? The walking dead game series proves that you can. Clementine is a the moral compass of the series and it\'s heart-wrenching to see what a little, sweet 8 year old has to go through to survive the zombie apocalypse. But Clementine is amazingly resolute, resourceful and shows great courage, patience and intelligence always finding a way out. She is written masterfully by the creator of the successful Walking dead graphic novel/TV show/Videogame and shows us that no matter how dire the situation is, you cannot lose hope. &lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ykyomNFJbn0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>Honarable Mention </rank><thumbnail>http://cdn01.wallconvert.com/_media/wp_400x250/1/2/14753.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>(The New) Lara Croft</itemname><description>I never really cared for Tomb Raider. All she was a sex symbol anyway.  I didn\'t really care for the old game\'s storyline or the Angelina Jolie\'s movies. I found them lacking any depth and having almost no emotional investment. 



But the 2013 reboot is an entirely different story. And I was delighted by the way Lara is portrayed. The new Lara finally has some solid dynamic character development through the game. And the new license looks promising... Time will tell how well does Square Enix develops the popular protagonist and gives her the depth and dimension she deserves. &lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ev02L2fmMJ0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item><item><rank>Honarable Mention </rank><thumbnail>http://static9.cdn.ubi.com/en-GB/images/far-cry-3-savages-vaas-midtcm2165303.jpg</thumbnail><itemname>Vaas Montenegro</itemname><description>Like Tiny Tina, Vaas was a minor character in Far Cry 3, but has become incredibly popular due to his dialogues and insane actions. 



The secondary antagonist of the game is loved by every Far Cry 3 player and featured as one of the main characters in the youtube miniseries called Far Cry experience due to his popularity.&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7ai3Maj9IZQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes></item></items></list>